<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The Game is On]]></title>
  <link href="http://bhrigu123.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bhrigu123.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-18T23:17:08+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://bhrigu123.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bhrigu Srivastava]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Game Is On]]></title>
    <link href="http://bhrigu123.github.io/blog/2015/06/18/the-game-is-on/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T23:01:16+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://bhrigu123.github.io/blog/2015/06/18/the-game-is-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So after setting up octopress and learning how to use it and deploy using Github, I have finally set out to blogging, which I wanted to start for a long time but was everytime too lazy to set up my computer.</p>

<p>Now, for a novice like me, this blogging technique is much different than the regular blogging websites, like Wordpress, since you have to work <!--more--> using the terminal (shell) of your system, and to be honest, it is much more fun this way. It gives you more of a hacker&rsquo;s feel as you have to do a lot of shell scripting. Moreover, markdown language makes writing posts easier as well as interesting.<br>
I&rsquo;m looking forward to explore the functionalities this blogging service can provide, and experiment with the third party plugins to get more features.</p>

<p>One more reason I couldn&rsquo;t start a blog earlier was that I wasn&rsquo;t sure about the content I would put in it. Now that I&rsquo;ve started competitive programming and some web development, I would post about problem solving skills and algorithms (as I learn along), web hacks/tricks, and also anything that is worth sharing and I find could be of service to you.</p>

<p>Comments and feedbacks are always welcome, and I am also keen to follow more blogs, so get in touch.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
