<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Bhrigu Srivastava</title>
    <link>https://bhrigu.me/tags/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Bhrigu Srivastava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016–2020, Bhrigu Srivastava; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:21:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhrigu.me/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020 - A Look back at the Year</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/2020-a-lookback-at-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:21:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/2020-a-lookback-at-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back at 2020, it was a confusing ride. The pandemic / lockdown had nothing to with that, for me at least. For me it was&amp;hellip;.really&amp;hellip;confusing, at a personal level. Not sure what other word to use to describe it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 23:22:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2015 I kicked off blogging when I discovered Octpress. It has been a great journey in my writing experience. I had started it to mostly comprise of technical articles. But over the time it evolved to be a collection of articles around productivity, projects and my life&amp;rsquo;s events as well (a journal of sorts), besides just the tech articles that I write.
What gives me high is the tremendous response I get on my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/2019-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/2019-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the March of 2020 now. I am super late this time to write about my last year in review blog post. The thing is, 2020 has been a super confusing ride from the beginning. And it&amp;rsquo;s just March. Anyways, more about 2020 next year. I&amp;rsquo;ll just take out some time now to write about 2019 while I am in Delhi for the Holi holidays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 of Strings and Beats</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/2018-of-strings-and-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/2018-of-strings-and-beats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, 2018 is over and it feels like it went by so fast. As compared to 2017 or &amp;lsquo;16, there might not be anything that was majorly interesting, but nonetheless, it was a good year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Blog</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/2018/11/05/test-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/2018/11/05/test-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, hey! Don&amp;rsquo;t mind, this is just a test blog. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have anything on my mind on what to put down on this one. I overslept the last night, had some relaxing nap some time later, and here I am super awake at midnight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 My Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/2016-my-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/2016-my-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2016 is almost over and I felt like writing again (which happens quite rarely). Trying to recollect few of the highilghts of this year, which was full of surprises, excitement and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad Moments Amazon Internship</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/hyderabad-moments-amazon-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/hyderabad-moments-amazon-internship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My 2 month internship at Amazon was an amazing experience and a new phase, be it living separately for the first time in a different city, or my first ever internship/job experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Game Is On</title>
      <link>https://bhrigu.me/post/the-game-is-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhrigu.me/post/the-game-is-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after setting up octopress and learning how to use it and deploy using Github, I have finally set out to blogging, which I wanted to start for a long time but was everytime too lazy to set up my computer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
